Jacob Cox

Full Stack Software Developer

Solutions-driven Software Engineer with 10+ years of project management experience in the manufacturing sector where my organizational skills and attention to detail helped realize a four-fold increase in sales during my tenure. Proficient in JavaScript and Python as well as relational and non-relational databases. Dedicated to empowering clients and co-workers to dream big, but build iteratively.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

GIMME5

Tools: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Local Storage, Words API, GitHub **Overview**: Exercise app for writers, guiding them through a series of writing prompts. Users' ideas are stored and later drawn upon to generate the first draft of a project.

WEB PAGE TEMPLATE

Tools: JavaScript, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Bootstrap, Heroku

Overview: Personal web site for my playwrighting work. Created a form that takes in information on a play (cast details, synopsis, production photos, etc.) and uses it to dynamically style a show page for each play that is added to the database, greatly reducing updating/maintenance time.

STOCK APP

Tools: Python, Flask, Peewee, Sqlite, Heroku, React-Bootstrap, React, AlphaVantage API

Overview: Stock tracking app that allows users to research stocks and build watchlists of equities that interest them. Price targets can be set with the user being alerted when they are triggered.

Chicago, IL (612) 916-5253

jacob@championofvictory.com

LinkedIn: <u>Jacob-Joseph-Cox</u>

GitHub: cox512

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap,
JavaScript, Node.js, JQuery,
React, EJS, Python, Flask,
SQLite, Peewee, MongoDB,
Mongoose, Express.js, APIs,
MVC Patterning, OOP,
Authentication, Excel,
Git/GitHub, Bash, AJAX,
Heroku

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Software Engineering Fellow 500+ hour training program focused on: Git/GitHub, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, MongoDB, SQL, Python, and React

Lawrence University

Appleton, WI BA Studio Art magna cum laude

SELECTED EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Banquet Captain/Server | Lettuce Entertain You | Chicago, IL | 2016-present

Oversee the planning and execution of small and large-scale corporate events and private parties ranging in size from 20 guests to 520.

- Organize crews of team members from a variety of backgrounds to work as a single unit by listening closely to their concerns, laying out a cohesive vision, and clearly delineating duties
- · Adaptable to ever-changing circumstances, re-orchestrating assignments on the fly to seamlessly transition from the old plan to the new one
- · Manage risk by foreseeing and mitigating potential issues on the client and organizational side

Keith Clayton Furniture | Chicago, IL | Project Manager | 2005–2016

Created joyful handmade furnishings for an array of clientele. Led a team of motivated artisans to achieve quick turnaround while maintaining product integrity.

- · Accomplished a 400+ percent increase in sales during my tenure without advertising
- Engaged entire build team in the project-planning process, elevating their personal stakes and improving product quality while minimizing costly communication lapses, resulting in a large upswing in repeat business and word-of-mouth recommendations
- · Organized and streamlined the budgeting, scheduling, production, and installation process to make best use of facility space and decrease the need for a costly expansion

Freelance Playwright | Chicago, IL | 2010-present

Award-winning, internationally produced writer of short- and long-form plays. In charge of crafting the artistic vision, production goals, messaging, and development strategy for dozens of rehearsal settings.

- · Producer of work for both stage and screen, including a month-long film shoot with an extensive fund-raising campaign and a crew of nearly 20, finishing production ahead of schedule.
- · Lead conductor of the years-long play creation process from initial concept and script generation, through the multi-tiered workshopping system, and into production

Fig Media | Chicago, IL | Video Editor | 2005–2006

Collaborated with a team of Producers and Videographers to develop personal documentaries as well as stylish corporate promotions using Final Cut Pro.

- · Worked hand-in-hand with clients in crafting a meticulous product, translating feedback into clearly articulated and actionable steps for the larger team
- · Researched and quickly implemented new graphic and motion software into my daily workflow and taught those new-found skills to a team of Editors, guiding them through the creation of an attention-getting multi-media marketing presentation at the Adler Planetarium